{
  "theory": {
    "intro": "<par>We know how to <skill-link>expand brackets</skill-link> like <inline-math/>. But what do we do if we have a multiplication of brackets with brackets? Like <inline-math/>? The answer is: we <term>expand brackets twice</term>. First we expand one, and then we expand the other.</par>",
    "rule": "<head>The rule</head><par>If we have a number multiplication, like for instance <inline-math/>, then we can visualize this multiplication using blocks.</par><block-drawing/><par>From this, we see that <inline-math/> can first be rewritten to <inline-math/> and then to <inline-math/>. Check for yourself: they all result into <inline-math/>.</par><par>This works exactly the same if we have an expression like <inline-math/>. Here, <inline-math/>, <inline-math/>, <inline-math/> and <inline-math/> can be any type of expression, like <inline-math/> or anything similar. We can again visualize this.</par><block-drawing/><par>From this visualization, we see that we may rewrite <inline-math/> to <inline-math/>. We call this <term>expanding double brackets</term>. The accompanying rule is <block-math/> You generally don't need to remember this rule. What you should remember is that you multiply each of the terms from the left brackets (here <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>) with each of the terms from the right brackets (here <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>). If you do this for all combinations of terms, you get the right result.</par>",
    "steps": "<head>The steps</head><par>To expand double brackets, like for instance with <inline-math/>, take the following steps.</par><list><item><a><skill-link>Expand the left brackets</skill-link>. (Or identically, you may start with the right set too.) Keep the other brackets as they are, treating them as a single number. For the example, this gives <block-math/></a></item><item><b>Continue by <skill-link>expanding the remaining brackets</skill-link>. For our example, this then gives<block-math/>Note that we can also use a short-cut by directly multiplying each of the terms of the left brackets with each of the terms of the right brackets.</b></item><item><c><skill-link>Merge similar terms</skill-link> - terms that are identical, apart from their number factor - into a single term. In the example, we merge <inline-math/> and <inline-math/> together into <inline-math/>.</c></item></list><par>The final result <inline-math/> is as easy as you can possibly write it.</par>"
  },
  "meta": {
    "learningGoals": "<par>In this skill you learn to <term>expand double brackets</term>. If we multiply a sum within brackets by another sum within brackets, like in <inline-math/>, you should be able to write this without brackets. In this example this results in <inline-math/>. This skill also includes somewhat more complicated terms in the sums inside said brackets and/or larger sums with more terms.</par>"
  },
  "practice": {
    "basicForm": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the fraction <block-math/> Simplify this fraction as much as possible. (Potential brackets do not have to be expanded.)",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Focus on the numeric factors first. Simplify these as much as possible, leaving the rest as is.",
        "solution": "The numbers inside the fraction equal <inline-math/>. We can divide both the numerator and the denominator by <inline-math/>, which leaves us with <inline-math/>. Writing this together with the (unchanged) variable factors, we get <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Cancel all possible variable factors, to further simplify the fraction.",
        "solution": "We can cancel <counting-word/> factors of <inline-math/> from both the numerator and the denominator, resulting in <block-math/> This is as simplified as possible. Altogether, the final result is <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Merge similar terms (with equal power of <inline-math/>) together to simplify the result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "There are two terms that have <inline-math/> as a factor, being <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>. Together these can be written as <inline-math/>. The resulting expression then becomes <block-math/> This is our final answer. In short, <inline-math/>."
      }
    },
    "higherPowers": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the expression <block-math/> Expand the brackets and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Expand the left set of brackets (here <inline-math/>) while keeping the right set of brackets (here <inline-math/>) intact. Treat the right set of brackets as a single number, which technically it is.",
        "solution": "We multiply each of the terms <inline-math/> and <inline-math/> in the left set of brackets by the full right brackets. This results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Expand all remaining brackets.",
        "solution": "Expanding the remaining brackets in the usual way results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Merge similar terms (with equal power of <inline-math/>) together to simplify the result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "There are two terms that have <inline-math/> as a factor, being <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>. Together these can be written as <inline-math/>. The resulting expression then becomes <block-math/> This is our final answer. In short, <inline-math/>."
      }
    },
    "multipleTerms": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the expression <block-math/> Expand the brackets and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Expand the left set of brackets (here <inline-math/>) while keeping the right set of brackets (here <inline-math/>) intact. Treat the right set of brackets as a single number, which technically it is.",
        "solution": "We multiply each of the terms <inline-math/> and <inline-math/> in the left set of brackets by the full right brackets. This results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Expand all remaining brackets.",
        "solution": "Expanding the remaining brackets in the usual way results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Merge similar terms (with equal power of <inline-math/>) together to simplify the result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "There are two terms that have <inline-math/> as a factor, being <inline-math/> and <inline-math/>. Together these can be written as <inline-math/>. Identically, <inline-math/> and <inline-math/> can be merged into <inline-math/>. The resulting expression then becomes <block-math/> This is our final answer. In short, <inline-math/>."
      }
    },
    "squared": {
      "mainProblem": "Consider the expression <block-math/> Expand the brackets and simplify the result as much as possible.",
      "step1": {
        "problem": "Use the definition of the square to rewrite <inline-math/> as a multiplication <inline-math/> without any square outside the brackets.",
        "solution": "A square simply means an expression multiplied by itself. So we can write <block-math/>"
      },
      "step2": {
        "problem": "Expand the left set of brackets, while keeping the right set of brackets intact. Treat the right set of brackets as a single number, which technically it is.",
        "solution": "We multiply each of the terms <inline-math/> and <inline-math/> in the left set of brackets by the full right brackets. This results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step3": {
        "problem": "Expand all remaining brackets.",
        "solution": "Expanding the remaining brackets in the usual way results in <block-math/>"
      },
      "step4": {
        "problem": "Merge similar terms (with equal power of <inline-math/>) together to simplify the result as much as possible.",
        "solution": "<par>There are two terms that have <inline-math/> as a factor, being <inline-math/> and again <inline-math/>. Together these can be written as <inline-math/>. The resulting expression then becomes <block-math/> This is our final answer. In short, <inline-math/>.</par><sub-head>Short-cut</sub-head><par>There is a possible short-cut for this question. A square of a sum, like <inline-math/>, always comes out as <inline-math/>. Using this knowledge, we could have also directly seen that <block-math/></par>"
      }
    }
  },
  "crossExerciseFeedback": {
    "wrongBracketsExpanded": "<a>Make sure to expand all brackets, except for <inline-math/>.</a>",
    "stillHasPower": "<a>There are still brackets with an exponent above it.</a>",
    "bracketProductRemains": "<a>Make sure to expand one set of brackets: you cannot have brackets multiplied by brackets anymore.</a>"
  }
}